perficient.com 2018-10-19

# Privacy Policy | Perficient, Inc

This Privacy Policy is effective as of May 25, 2018 and applies to any Perficient website regardless of how you access or use such site.  Please note that this policy may be updated, without notice to you, reflecting any changes in the way we handle your personal data or any changes in applicable laws.

Perficient is committed to protecting the privacy of your information and implementing technology that gives you a rewarding and safe online experience. We want you to feel secure when visiting our site and are committed to maintaining your privacy when doing so.

## **1. What Information We Gather and How We Use It**

Information on Perficient.com and other Perficient websites is gathered in two ways: directly and indirectly. Perficient will at times ask you to directly provide information that personally identifies you (registering for an event, downloading a file, signing up for an email list, etc.). It is our policy to keep personal information only as long as needed to fulfill the purposes for which the information was collected.

We do not generally seek to collect sensitive or personal information through this site or in general.  In cases where such data is collected, we do so in accordance with data privacy laws and requirements, and/or ask for your consent. 

We may collect personal data of our employees, potential employees, clients, suppliers, business contacts, shareholders and website users: 

1.1 Information gathered from website users.  Perficient may collect personal information in two ways: (a) directly (e.g., you provide personal data to sign up for events, newsletters or to request information), or (b) indirectly (such as what is gathered through our website’s technology).  Perficient does not require that you provide your personal data in order to receive information about our Services and offerings, but to the extent you have provided such information we may keep a record of that correspondence for continued marketing contact, or for survey or research purposes.  Our website may collect personal data about your computer, including (where available) your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration, traffic filtering, statistical reporting or troubleshooting of errors within our systems.  Please see the Cookies section below for more information with regard to how we handle information indirectly collected. 

Perficient may use your personal data to: (i) process online job applications, (ii) fulfill your requests for continued receipt of white papers, articles, newsletters or other content, (iii) for surveys or research questionnaires you have agreed to take part in, (iv) contact you for marketing purposes when you have agreed to this action, and (v) personalize or improve your experience at our website when feedback is provided by you. 

Retention and use of your personal information for the purposes mentioned above is solely based on your prior consent, to the extent such consent is mandatory under applicable laws. 

1.2 Information used for marketing purposes:  The bulk of personal information Perficient collects and uses for marketing purposes relates to individual employees of our clients and other companies with which we have existing business relationships.  We may also obtain and maintain contact information from other sources, including content made public at social media websites, to make an initial contact with a relevant individual at a potential client or other company.  We may also combine data from publicly-available sources, as well as from our email, website and personal interactions with you to better assess your experience with Perficient. 

Perficient does use customer relationship management database (CRM) technology to manage and track these marketing efforts, which may include personal information belonging to the individuals mentioned above, which could include contact data, publicly available information, your responses to targeted email, website activity of registered users of our website and other business information included by Perficient employees regarding any contact they may have with you. 

If you wish to be excluded from our CRM database, please contact us at [datasecurity@perficient.com](mailto:datasecurity@perficient.com).  Also, you can exercise your rights to refuse any marketing communications by utilizing opt-out mechanisms in emails we send to you.  In such cases, we will retain minimum personal data to note your request(s) in order to avoid contacting you again.

## **2. Information Retention/Destruction**

Perficient may retain your personal information only for as long as necessary, and has policies and processes in place so that such information is deleted after a reasonable period of time according to applicable law.  Such data is retained for as long as we have an ongoing relationship with you or for as long as needed to provide services to you, and for as long as needed in order to comply with our global legal and contractual obligations. 

## **3. Cookies and IP Data **

We use “cookies” on this site, as well as our affiliated sites. A cookie is a piece of data stored on your device to help us improve your access to our site and identify repeat visitors. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.  We also collect information indirectly through our Internet access logs. When you visit Perficient.com, your Internet Protocol (IP) address is automatically collected and is placed in our Internet access logs. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. Your IP address is used to help diagnose any technical problems, analyze site trends, administer the site, track movement within the site, and gather broad demographic information about site use that can eventually be used to make improvements that enhance your user experience on Perficient.com. Except as otherwise specifically set forth in this Privacy Policy, Perficient does not sell, exchange, trade or give away personal information you voluntarily provide to us to any outside sources. 

By visiting Perficient.com (or their affiliated sites) you agree that we can place these cookies on your device.  Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions.  A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser.  You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent.  

Web beacons, conversion pixels and other technologies for similar purposes may be included on these sites, in marketing emails or our newsletters to determine whether messages have been opened and links clicked on.  Web beacons do not place information on your device but may work together with cookies to monitor website activity.  The information provided in this Section 3 also applies to this technology.  “Conversion pixels” are small codes located on web page which may be triggered when someone visits a page resulting in an increase in the conversion count. 

Perficient may analyze your IP and browser information to determine what is most effective about our website, to help us identify ways to improve it and, eventually, to determine who we can make improvements to provide a better user experience. 

Further examples of the information we may gather with these cookies, and how it is used, is set forth in Section 1, above. 

## **4. Third Parties **

Perficient may transfer personal data to our service providers, professional advisors, public and governmental authorities or third parties in connection with any potential corporate or commercial transaction, provided such parties comply with the same measures of confidentiality and security of Perficient, itself. 

We use tracking code from third party companies, such as Google Analytics and Linkedin to provide us with visitor behavior data and intelligence about our sites. These companies use programming code to collect information about your interaction with our sites, such as the pages you visit, the links you click on and how long you are on our sites. For more information on how these companies collect and use information on our behalf, please refer to their privacy policies: Google at [Google Privacy & Terms](https://policies.google.com/?hl=en) and Linkedin at [Linkedin Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy). 

You should be aware that some third parties may be located in other countries.  Before we affect any transfer of your personal information, Perficient will take all necessary steps to ensure your personal information will remain protected as required by any applicable data privacy laws and our own internal policies.  Any transfers of your personal information to third parties in other countries will be based on an adequacy decision and will be performed pursuant to all applicable laws. 

## **5. Your Rights and Choices with Regard to Your Personal Information **

You have the right (under the conditions, and subject to the exceptions, of applicable law) to: 

a) Request access to any personal information of yours or about you that Perficient processes, or request it be transmitted to another Data Controller.  This right entitles you to know whether we hold personal information about you and, if we do, to obtain information on and a copy of that personal information.  Also, you may request that Perficient transmit any of your personal information in its possession to another Data Controller. 

b) Request changes or corrections to any of your personal information that we process.  You may request Perficient make changes to your personal information in our possession if you feel it is inaccurate or incomplete.  

c) Object to the processing or request erasure of your personal information or restrict the processing of your personal information.  These rights entitle you to request that Perficient no longer process your personal information and erase it from our systems, including where such personal information would no longer be necessary, or to request that Perficient only process your personal information in limited circumstances (including only with your consent). 

You have the right to withdraw your consent to Perficient’s use of, or retention of, your personal information at any time, for any reason, subject to applicable laws.  Please note that this will not affect Perficient’s right to process such personal information obtained prior to any withdrawal of your consent, or to continue parts of any processing allowed by applicable laws. 

If you feel that your data privacy and security rights have been violated by Perficient, we welcome your feedback and encourage such individuals to contact [datasecurity@perficient.com](mailto:datasecurity@perficient.com) and/or [privacyofficer@perficient.com](mailto:privacyofficer@perficient.com) first to seek resolution of any complaint.  You, of course, have the right at all times to file a complaint directly with any relevant supervisory or regulatory authority or to make a claim with any competent court.  

When we collect information from you through a web form, you may tell us that you do not want it to be used for further marketing contact. You may also turn off cookies in your browser. 

## **6. Opt-Out Information **

Perficient may on occasion send email communication regarding events, webinars, guides, marketing content, its services, etc.  You may also receive direct outreach from authorized Perficient representatives.  We will always provide such recipients a clear and easy means to opt-out of receiving any future communication by clicking the unsubscribe link contained in the email communication or by directly replying to the Perficient sender.  We will honor unsubscribe requests within 10 days from the time of request if sent via email.  Unsubscribe requests via the ‘unsubscribe link’ in the footer of a Perficient email will be honored immediately.  Unsubscribe requests will never expire. 

Further, you may request at any time and for any reason that Perficient remove your personal information from its systems, or restrict the use of your personal information, pursuant to Section 5, above. 

## **7. Site Security **

Perficient recognizes the importance of your right to privacy and protection of your personal information and takes all measures in compliance with applicable laws and our own data privacy and security policies and procedures.  Further, Perficient protects all internal systems that may maintain or access your personal information against unauthorized or unlawful access or processing, as well as against accidental loss, alteration, disclosure, or accidental or unlawful destruction of or damage of your data in our possession.

Perficient maintains organizational, physical and technical security arrangements for all personal information that we retain, with controls, policies, processes, procedures and guidance to maintain such information that takes into account any risk associated with the categories of personal information, as well as any processing of such personal information by Perficient. 

When using our websites, you should understand the open nature of the internet is such that information and personal information flows over networks connecting you to our systems without security measures and, as such, such information may be accessed or used by people other than those for whom the information is intended. 

## **8. Your Acceptance of These Terms**

By using Perficient.com or any of its affiliated websites, you provide your consent to this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this policy at any time at our discretion. Please check this page periodically for changes.  This site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such third-party sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy policy statements of any other site that collects information from you. 

## **9. Compliance with All Applicable Laws**

Perficient complies with all applicable laws in securing the privacy of your information, including those set forth by U.S.-EU Privacy Shield, the General Data Protection Regulations, U.S.-Swiss Privacy Shield, and more regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Perficient adheres to all Privacy Principles set forth with regard to notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.

## **10. Questions? **

If you have any questions about Perficient’s Website Privacy Policy, this website, or your dealings with this website, please contact us at [datasecurity@perficient.com](mailto:datasecurity@perficient.com) or you may contact us through our [Contact page](https://www.perficient.com/contact).
